https://www.schoonersail.com/sailing-holiday-booking/terms-conditions/

Home » Booking » Terms And Conditions
SchoonerSail
Booking Terms and Conditions
SchoonerSail Limited (referred to here as SchoonerSail) cannot accept bookings from anyone who is pregnant, is a carrier of a serious communicable disease (such as Hepatitis B) or has epilepsy. SchoonerSail reserves the right to refuse any booking which in its sole opinion might affect the safety of Trinovante or anyone on board.
Please do not pay for or finalise any travel arrangements until we have confirmed in writing that we accept your booking. SchoonerSail will confirm your booking by email after a booking form has been filled in, accepted and the initial voyage payment has been made. A contract exists between us from the date we confirm your booking to you in writing
Print SchoonerSail Terms And Conditions PDF
1. Your voyage fee includes
a. accommodation on board and all meals on board
b. use of life jackets, lines and sailing waterproofs/thermal suits
c. harbour dues,mooring fees and fuel
2. Your voyage fee does not include
a. travel to and from the boat,  you are solely responsible for arranging and paying for your travel to and from the boat.
b. travel insurance, you are solely responsible for arranging and paying for your travel insurance.
c. bedding – crew bring their own sleeping bag and pillowcase, a pillow is provided
d. any meals you choose to take ashore
3. Booking, Payment and Cancellation Terms
a. 50% of the voyage fee is payable when your booking is accepted. This is non refundable outside of the stated cancellation period (section c below). Make sure your travel insurance covers you for cancellation.
The balance of 50% is payable when you arrive on board or shortly before if you prefer.
b. You are liable for the balance of 50% from 8 weeks before your voyage starts unless we receive a written cancellation by email before that date and have confirmed receipt of this to you by email. If you think you will need to cancel do be fair to us and get in touch at the earliest available opportunity.
c. You may cancel at any time within 14 days of your booking being confirmed by email if the voyage starts more than 8 weeks from your booking date and we will the refund any payments received. If the voyage starts within eight weeks of your booking you may cancel at any time within 48 hours and we will refund any payments received.
4. Travel Insurance / Passports
a. You must obtain travel suitable insurance cover for all voyages apart from Taster Weekends in the UK and provide SchoonerSail with the details of the insurer, their 24 hour emergency telephone number and your policy number at the start of the voyage. The type of insurance you need, Offshore or Coastal is noted on the voyage notes on our website and will be advised on your booking confirmation.
You cannot sail if you are unable to provide SchoonerSail with valid insurance details at the start of the voyage. Please make sure you have read the notes on the SchoonerSail web site on buying sailing holiday insurance.
b.If you fail to travel with valid and adequate sailing travel insurance we will not be liable for any losses which reasonable sailing travel insurance would be expected to cover. Make sure the insurance you buy is valid for your voyage.
c. You must have a full passport for all foreign voyages and provide your passport details to SchoonerSail at the start of the voyage. You cannot sail if you do not have a valid passport with you at the start of any voyage sailing outside of the UK. If you are a non EU National please contact us for more information.
d. SchoonerSail accepts no responsibility for any personal belongings you bring on board – please make sure you are adequately insured.
5. The Voyage
a. You acknowledge that sailing can be a dangerous activity, which can be both physically and mentally challenging, especially in rough weather which can occur at any time during any voyage or Taster weekend.
b. SchoonerSail will make every effort not to change or cancel any advertised voyage however reasons beyond our control including, but not limited to, unsuitable weather can make this necessary; therefore ports of joining, leaving and ports of call are not guaranteed. Your booking is also subject to the regulatory environment allowing the voyage to take place. If a voyage is cancelled prior to the advertised start date all voyage fees paid will be refunded in full but SchoonerSail, the skipper and/or crew shall otherwise have no liability whatsoever for the vessel not fulfilling or completing the advertised itinerary.
c. You will be actively participating in sailing Trinovante. Voyages over 8 hours operate on a watch system and you will be part of a watch. SchoonerSail do not take non participating guests on board.
d. For reasons of safety you agree to follow the instructions of the skipper and/or his delegated representative at all times and to participate fully in any instruction,safety briefing, or training that is being given.
e. The skipper and/or his delegated representative’s decision is final in all matters relating to the safe operation of Trinovante and her tenders.
f. For reasons of safety alcohol is only consumed at the skippers discretion and never at sea. This does not mean Trinovante is a ‘dry’ boat – you can drink on board just not when we are underway or may get underway. Smokers may smoke on deck.
g. You understand that SchoonerSail voyages are often well off the beaten track in wilderness areas therefore you may have to get on and off the boat using dock side ladders, by climbing over other boats etc. Do not expect to be stepping on and off marina pontoons. Please make sure you meet the required fitness levels before you book – if you are in doubt ask us. Sailing on Trinovante is more of an expedition type of experience than a holiday.
h. No animals, unlawful drugs, weapons, or goods of any kind are to be brought on board.
i. Guests under the age of 18 by special arrangement only.
j. SchoonerSail is not responsible for sailing guests while they are ashore
k. It is customary for sailing guests to get involved with the washing up onboard
l. You agree to provide your own waterproof non-slip footwear suitable for wet conditions.
6. Health and Safety. Remember these conditions are aimed at your safety not ours.
Be aware that you will be out of reach of the usual shore-side emergency medical services on all voyages and taster weekends.
a. It is a condition of booking that you have a level of health and fitness sufficient to allow you to actively participate in all activities on board. If you are in any doubt as to what to expect whilst sailing on board Trinovante, or you have any questions about filling in the booking form do ring us on the boat phone for a chat. We are not medical experts but we can describe likely ‘at sea conditions’ and discuss general issues with you.
As a rough guide line a good level of agility is much more important than brute physical strength or aerobic fitness. If you are significantly overweight such that your agility is affected it is likely you will struggle with activities onboard.
b. Failure to declare information relevant to your medical fitness and/or your ability to actively participate in sailing on board may result in you not being allowed to sail and/or to continue with a voyage if the captain feels that your safety or the safety of others may be put at risk. No refunds or travel allowances will be given if you have to leave the boat for this reason.
c. You must notify SchoonerSail of any changes in your health and fitness that arise between booking and sailing.
d. You agree to provide a letter from your GP, at your own expense, on a form provided by SchoonerSail stating your fitness to sail on a specified voyage, if it is deemed necessary by SchoonerSail.
e. In the event of medical emergency you agree to reimburse SchoonerSail for any expenses that may be incurred for medical treatment and/or evacuation from the vessel and/or repatriation.
f. You must inform the captain of any medication that you are taking whilst you are on board. If you are taking medication please make sure to consult your doctor about any problems seasickness may cause with your medication and the suitability of any seasickness remedies you might be taking. If you will need seasickness medication make sure you bring enough with you.
g. Special dietary requirements must be advised at the time of booking.
All of the above may lead you to think you must be super fit to sail with us. This is not the case and we do our best to facilitate people so please do phone us for a chat if you are unsure. Our main concern is that your holiday is safe and enjoyable.
7 Privacy policy
a. SchoonerSail will not pass your details or personal information to other organizations or persons except for reasons of health and safety, border control issues and/or legal reasons.
8 Correspondence
a. All communications will be by email to the email address used on your booking form unless arranged otherwise. Communication by postal services may incur and additional charge.
9 Everything else
a. SchoonerSail shall not be liable in any manner whatsoever for any loss, damage or injury whether direct or indirect, economic or consequential arising from these terms and conditions of booking .
b. This contract is governed by English law and any claims or disputes relating to this contract are subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts of England.
c. SchoonerSail reserves the right to change these terms and conditions without notice.
d. All written communication is by email unless specifically agreed in advance.
h. Trinovante is regulated by the MCA in the UK. Last Revision 25-04-18
7. Privacy policy
a. SchoonerSail will not pass your details or personal information to other organizations or persons except for reasons of health and safety, border control issues and/or legal reasons.
Please see our separate Privacy Policy for full details
8. Correspondence
a. All communications will be by email to the email address used on your booking form unless arranged otherwise. Communication by postal services may incur and additional charge.
9. Everything else
a. SchoonerSail shall not be liable in any manner whatsoever for any loss, damage or injury whether direct or indirect, economic or consequential arising from these terms and conditions of booking .
b. This contract is governed by English law and any claims or disputes relating to this contract are subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts of England.
c. SchoonerSail reserves the right to change these terms and conditions without notice.
d. All written communication is by email unless specifically agreed in advance.
h. Trinovante is regulated by the MCA in the UK.
Last Revision 25-04-18
SchoonerSail Newsletters Sign Up for Early Bird offers and more.
SchoonerSail1k+ likesOpen facebook page nowJoin our Facebook community
SchoonerSail Limited
16A Stafford Mill
London Road
Thrupp
Stroud
Gloucestershire
GL5 2A
Ships phone +44 (0)7977 594 649
info@schoonersail.com
Company No 06133553
Scroll to top
This site uses cookies. By continuing to browse the site, you are agreeing to our use of cookies.OKNo, Read MoreCookie and Privacy Settings
How we use cookies
We may request cookies to be set on your device. We use cookies to let us know when you visit our websites, how you interact with us, to enrich your user experience, and to customize your relationship with our website.
Click on the different category headings to find out more. You can also change some of your preferences. Note that blocking some types of cookies may impact your experience on our websites and the services we are able to offer.
Essential Website Cookies
These cookies are strictly necessary to provide you with services available through our website and to use some of its features.
Because these cookies are strictly necessary to deliver the website, refuseing them will have impact how our site functions. You always can block or delete cookies by changing your browser settings and force blocking all cookies on this website. But this will always prompt you to accept/refuse cookies when revisiting our site.
We fully respect if you want to refuse cookies but to avoid asking you again and again kindly allow us to store a cookie for that. You are free to opt out any time or opt in for other cookies to get a better experience. If you refuse cookies we will remove all set cookies in our domain.
We provide you with a list of stored cookies on your computer in our domain so you can check what we stored. Due to security reasons we are not able to show or modify cookies from other domains. You can check these in your browser security settings.
Check to enable permanent hiding of message bar and refuse all cookies if you do not opt in. We need 2 cookies to store this setting. Otherwise you will be prompted again when opening a new browser window or new a tab.
Click to enable/disable essential site cookies.
Google Analytics Cookies
These cookies collect information that is used either in aggregate form to help us understand how our website is being used or how effective our marketing campaigns are, or to help us customize our website and application for you in order to enhance your experience.
If you do not want that we track your visit to our site you can disable tracking in your browser here:
Click to enable/disable Google Analytics tracking.
Other external services
We also use different external services like Google Webfonts, Google Maps, and external Video providers. Since these providers may collect personal data like your IP address we allow you to block them here. Please be aware that this might heavily reduce the functionality and appearance of our site. Changes will take effect once you reload the page.
Google Webfont Settings:
Click to enable/disable Google Webfonts.
Google Map Settings:
Click to enable/disable Google Maps.
Google reCaptcha Settings:
Click to enable/disable Google reCaptcha.
Vimeo and Youtube video embeds:
Click to enable/disable video embeds.
Other cookies
The following cookies are also needed - You can choose if you want to allow them:
Click to enable/disable _ga - Google Analytics Cookie.
Click to enable/disable _gid - Google Analytics Cookie.
Click to enable/disable _gat_* - Google Analytics Cookie.
Privacy Policy
You can read about our cookies and privacy settings in detail on our Privacy Policy Page.
Privacy Policy
Home2020 Itinerary
All 2020 Sailing HolidaysTaster Weekend UKIpswich To BergenBergen To StavangerStavanger To SandefjordSandefjord To GothenburgGothenburg To CopenhagenCopenhagen To KielKiel To SAIL AmsterdamSAIL Amsterdam to Den HelderDen Helder To IpswichIpswich To London Back
Our Sailing Holidays
Life OnboardWhere We SailCrew StoriesSailing VideosOffshore SailingLearn To Sail | Sail TrainingSailing In Norway Back
The Ship
About The ShipSail PlanHistory Back
Booking
How To BookOnline Booking FormTravel To The ShipFAQSWhat To PackSailing Holiday InsurancePayment PageTerms And ConditionsPrivacy Policy Back
Tall Ships & Schooners
Tall Ships & SchoonersTall Ships Race FilmsTall Ships GalleryLearn To Sail A SchoonerSchooner BooksSchooner Rig Back
Contact
× Close Panel
